questions = [
    {
        group:"Easy as 3.1415962...",
        title:"O Wisdom where art thou?",
        question:"Where does Wisdom come from?",
        answers:["Your brain","Books","Friends; family","Martin Luther","God"],
        correct:"God",
        value:10,
    },
    {
        group:"An exercise in reality.",
        title:"You and your friend Johannes.",
        question:"You and your friend Johannes are out on the town, when you decide to steal a candy from a baby. If Johannes was truly your friend, what would he do?",
        answers:["Encourage you to steal more candy, and maybe a car.","Tell the baby's mother, and maybe your mom too.","Turn a blind eye.","Steal the baby's stroller.","Run away and hide."],
        correct:"Tell the baby's mother, and maybe your mom too.",
        value:30,
    },
    {
        group:"Easy as 3.1415962...",
        title:"In the beginning.",
        question:"What was the most important piece of the formation of the Universe?",
        answers:["Earth, wind, water fire.","Wisdom","Quarks and photons","The Bible","Luck"],
        correct:"Wisdom",
        value:50,
    },
    {
        group:"God is Good",
        title:"Be afraid, be very afraid.",
        question:"Which action best demonstrates 'Fear of the Lord'?",
        answers:["Giving thanks before a meal.","Hiding under a rock.","Listening to your Bible Study instructor, without question.","Crying when you here someone say 'God'.","Skipping church."],
        correct:"Giving thanks before a meal.",
        value:40,
    },
    {
        group:"Hard",
        title:"Whereforth art thou Proverbs?",
        question:"What is one reason we study Proverbs?",
        answers:["It is the easiest book of the bible.","Proverbs can help us in our daily lives.","It is the only book relevant to our lives.","This is the one source of God's Wisdom.","Michael wanted to study this, and he is perfect."],
        correct:"Proverbs can help us in our daily lives.",
        value:10,
    },
    {
        group:"Esoteric Extravaganza",
        title:"Here they are, its the...",
        question:"Which one of these song lyrics from the Beatles most resembles what we learned from Proverbs?",
        answers:["Here comes the sun.","Happiness is a warm gun.","Whisper words of wisdom, let it be.","All you need is love.","We all live in a yellow submarine."],
        correct:"All you need is love.",
        value:10,
    },
    {
        group:"Esoteric Extravaganza",
        title:"Elementary my dear Watson.",
        question:"Which of the following does Sir Arthur Conrad Doyle see as clear evidence of God?",
        answers:["A simple flower.","The spinning cosmos.","Fire","The sun and moon.","Humans"],
        correct:"A simple flower.",
        value:50,
    },
    {
        group:"God is Good",
        title:"The capable wife.",
        question:"Which of the following traits is most important for a capable wife?",
        answers:["Does housework.","Loves her husband.","Fears the Lord","Works hard.","Supports her family."],
        correct:"Fears the Lord",
        value:30,
    },
    {
        group:"An exercise in reality.",
        title:"Chocolate covered...",
        question:"What would proverbs say we should learn from ants?",
        answers:["Tiny is better.","We need no king, whatsoever.","To acheive any task, we should work together.","Farming is the highest achievement of man.","We should prepare for hard times when times are good."],
        correct:"We should prepare for hard times when times are good.",
        value:40,
    },
    {
        group:"Quixotic Quotes",
        title:"Proverbs 15",
        question:"A kind word turns aside _____, but a harsh word stirs up anger.",
        answers:["Love","Jealousy","Hatred","Wrath","Foolishness"],
        correct:"Wrath",
        value:10,
    },
    {
        group:"Quixotic Quotes",
        title:"Proverbs 27",
        question:"'Iron sharpens iron, so man sharpens another man.'  Explain.",
        answers:["When one person runs into another, they become sharp.",
                 "Who we are is refined through human interaction.",
                 "We become smarter by talking to other people.",
                 "We cannot learn anything from books.",
                 "Wisdom can only be found through other people."],
        correct:"Who we are is refined through human interaction.",
        value:30,
    },
    {
        group:"Quixotic Quotes",
        title:"Proverbs 17",
        question:"A ____ loves at all times.",
        answers:["Wife","Lover","Friend","Enemy","Preacher"],
        correct:"Friend",
        value:20,
    },
    {
        group:"Hard",
        title:"'You are so incredibly talented...'",
        question:"What does Proverbs suggest is so bad about flattery?",
        answers:["It inflates our ego.","It is always just a big lie.","It does not help us become better people.",
                 "It makes us feel good.","We learn to like people who hate us."],
        correct:"It does not help us become better people.",
        value:40,
    },
    {
        group:"Easy as 3.1415962...",
        title:"A little gold opens doors.",
        question:"Bribery works, but what about those who accept bribes?",
        answers:["They get rich.","They do right for the people.","They are wicked.","The greatest people take bribes.","They are trustworthy."],
        correct:"They are wicked.",
        value:40,
    },
    {
        group:"Easy as 3.1415962...",
        title:"All the lonely people",
        question:"How should we view the poor?",
        answers:["Ewwww...disgusting.","They did something wrong to become poor.","Clearly they are Lazy.","We should give them money so they go away.","Love them, they are God's children."],
        correct:"Love them, they are God's children.",
        value:30,
    },
    {
        group:"Easy as 3.1415962...",
        title:"Our most beloved",
        question:"What is one way parents may show they really love their child?",
        answers:["Giving their child 30,000 chocolate bars","Putting their child on the street.","Disciplining their child for misbehavior.","Telling the child 'I love you'.","It is impossible for a parent to love a child."],
        correct:"Disciplining their child for misbehavior.",
        value:20,
    },
    {
        group:"An exercise in reality.",
        title:"You and your friend Johannes, again.",
        question:"You are out on the town one evening, with your friend Johannes. You are approached by a women, who says 'come friends, I have some sweet bread I took from the soup kitchen.  We can eat until we are stuffed.' What should you do?",
        answers:["Push Johannes down, and run to eat your fill.","Go eat, stolen bread is sweet.","Eat bread, thank her, and move on.","Decline, as the bread was meant for the poor.","Steal the bread from the woman and binge with Johannes."],
        correct:"Decline, as the bread was meant for the poor.",
        value:50,
    },
    {
        group:"Hard",
        title:"Tight rope walking.",
        question:"Why are false balances so abhorrent?",
        answers:["Using them is as bad as stealing.","They represent indifference to others.","It always leads to the death of other people.",
                 "They make bad people rich.","They start wars."],
        correct:"They represent indifference to others.",
        value:50,
    },
    {
        group:"Hard",
        title:"Whom do you represent?",
        question:"A capable wife is really an image of ____.",
        answers:["The perfect wife","The perfect husband","God","A good king","The perfect person"],
        correct:"God",
        value:30,
    },
    {
        group:"God is Good",
        title:"It is blind.",
        question:"Why is justice a joy to the righteous, but fear to evil people?",
        answers:["Justice is killing evil people.","Justice brings riches to the righteous.",
                 "Justice is a quality of God.","Evil people fear everything.","Just people always love what evil people fear."],
        correct:"Justice is a quality of God.",
        value:20,
    },
    {
        group:"God is Good",
        title:"Love's power",
        question:"What is the true meaning of 'love covers all offenses'?",
        answers:["We need to find love.  Immediately.","If you are in a loving relationship, you cannot do wrong.",
                 "If you love someone you cannot make them angry.","Through God's love our sins are forgiven.","Through love we can fix all out problems."],
        correct:"Through God's love our sins are forgiven.",
        value:50,
    },
    {
        group:"God is Good",
        title:"Meet your maker",
        question:"Who did God make?",
        answers:["Rich people","Celebrities","Poor people","Fools","All people"],
        correct:"All people",
        value:10,
    },
    {
        group:"Hard",
        title:"There is no rest for the...",
        question:"Why should we not envy the wicked?",
        answers:["Evil will land us in jail.","The wicked will not love us.","It sets our hearts on things opposing God.","The wicked will turn on us.","It is not the best way to get rich."],
        correct:"It sets our hearts on things opposing God.",
        value:20,
    },
    {
        group:"An exercise in reality.",
        title:"One heart reflects another.",
        question:"Your friend yells at you, how should you respond?",
        answers:["Speak softly and kindly in return.","Yell back.","Disown your friend.","Tell your friend's mother.","Tell your friend to please shut up."],
        correct:"Speak softly and kindly in return.",
        value:20,
    },
    {
        group:"An exercise in reality.",
        title:"Whom do you seek?",
        question:"What should you seek first?",
        answers:["Money","A Spouse","Fine Things","God","Good Friends"],
        correct:"God",
        value:10,
    },
    {
        group:"Quixotic Quotes",
        title:"Proverbs 30",
        question:"'Do not add to His words, or else he will rebuke you.' What does this mean?",
        answers:["Only quote the Bible","You can say anything you'd like in the name of God",
                 "Don't teach about God.","Do not use God as way to spread your agenda.","God does not like people talking about Him."],
        correct:"Do not use God as way to spread your agenda.",
        value:40,
    },
    {
        group:"Quixotic Quotes",
        title:"Proverbs 3",
        question:"'Long life is in her right hand; in her left hand are riches and honor'  Who is she?",
        answers:["God","Wisdom","Righteousness","Deception","Hard work"],
        correct:"Wisdom",
        value:50,
    },
    {
        group:"Esoteric Extravaganza",
        title:"Remember Sampson?",
        question:"Which concept from proverbs would have helped Sampson?",
        answers:["A contentious wife should be avoided.","Do not eat stolen bread.","Always be prepared.","Protect the poor.","Wisdom comes from God."],
        correct:"A contentious wife should be avoided.",
        value:30,
    },
    {
        group:"Esoteric Extravaganza",
        title:"On Shakespearean morality",
        question:"We acted a bit of Hamlet, what was Hamlet's biggest mistake?",
        answers:["He killed his Uncle.","He was a bad Son to his mother.","He returned evil for evil.",
                 "He failed to listen to his friends.","He was born in Denmark."],
        correct:"He returned evil for evil.",
        value:40,
    },
    {
        group:"Esoteric Extravaganza",
        title:"Arghs, Monsters!!!",
        question:"What lesson in Proverbs is shown by Mike and Sully in Monster's, Inc.?",
        answers:["A good friend sticks with you.","Do not cheat you neighbors.","A good spouse puts the family first.",
                 "Do not envy the evil.","God loves His children."],
        correct:"A good friend sticks with you.",
        value:20,
    },
];